So let's talk about life.
我们来聊聊实际生活的例子
There are two errors that sometimes we make in life.
有时我们在生活中会犯两种错误
One is trying to kill Godzilla with a flyswatter.
第一种是用苍蝇拍来杀死哥斯拉龙
That's a pretty bad error to make.
这是非常愚蠢的错误
It's oversimplifying the problem we're trying to solve.
它过度简化了我们要解决的问题
The other one is to try to kill a fly with a bazooka.
另一种是用火箭筒杀死苍蝇
That's also pretty bad.
这也非常不实际
It's overcomplicating the problem we're trying to solve.
它过度复杂化了我们要解决的问题
In machine learning, these two types of errors are very easy to make.
在机器学习中 我们也非常容易犯这两种错误
When we oversimplify the problem, we call this underfitting.
当我们过度简化问题时 我们称之为欠拟合
And when we overcomplicate the problem, we call it overfitting.
过度复杂化时 称之为过拟合
So let's look at underfitting and overfitting in a bit more detail.
我们更详细地认识一下过拟合和欠拟合
Let's look at this classification problem.
先看这样一个分类问题
We need to find a property that separates the set on the left
我们需要找到一个属性 将左边的集合
from the set on the right.
与右边的集合分开
It seems like the solution is easy.
看起来解决方法很简单
The set on the right is made of dogs, and
右边的集合元素都是狗
the set on the left is made of things that are not dogs.
左边的集合元素都不是
But what if we oversimplify this?
如果我们过度简化它会怎样？
What if we say the set on the right is made of animals, and
假如我们说右边的都是动物
the set on the left is made of everything but animals?
而左边的都不是动物
Then our model is is a bit too simple.
那么我们的模型就太简单了
And we can see that it already makes a mistake on the training set,
而且可以看出我们已在训练集中犯了一个错误
since it misclassified this cat on the left side.
因为猫被错误地分类到了左边
This oversimplification is called underfitting.
这种过度简化成为欠拟合
One characteristic of it is that it doesn't do well on the training set.
它的一个特点是训练集的拟合不够好
We call this type of error an error due to bias.
我们称这种类型为偏差引起的误差
The other mistake we can make is to overcomplicate the model.
我们会犯的另一个错误是过度复杂化模型
If instead of describing the set on the right as dogs, we describe it as
这次我们不将右边的集合描述为狗
dogs that are wagging their tail, then this seems to do the job well in
而是摇着尾巴的狗 这看起来在训练集中
training set, but somehow our intuition is telling us that this is not right.
的拟合效果会很好 但直觉告诉我们这样做不对
This can be confirmed when you bring out a new instance.
在出现一个新实例时你就明白了
For example, this dog over here.
例如这里这只狗
Our logic tells us this dog should belong to the set on the right.
逻辑告诉我们这只狗应该属于右边的集合
But since the dog is not wagging its tail,
但由于这只狗没有摇尾巴
then this model mistakenly classifies it in the set on the left.
此模型会错误地将它分类到左边的集合
This error is called overfitting, this means the model is too specific.
此错误称为过拟合 也就是说此模型太过具体
One characteristic of it is that it does well in the training set but
它的一个特点是它在训练集中表现良好
it tends to memorize it instead of learning the characteristics of it, so
但它趋向于记住而不是学习数据的特点
it will not do well on the testing set.
因此在测试集上的表现不好
We call this type of error an error due to variance.
我们称这种错误为方差引起的误差
Let's get more technical.
从技术层面来说
In our regression example, we can see underfitting as follows.
在回归示例中 可以看到下面这样的欠拟合
Let's look at the points on the left.
看看左边的点
It seems like the correct model for
看起来这些点的正确模型
this point is a quadratic equation like this one.
是像这样的二次方程
We could try to model it as a line, but this won't work too well,
我们可以尝试将它拟合成一条直线 但效果不太好
since it's too simple.
因为它太简单了
The model won't do well in our training set.
此模型在训练集上的效果不好
This is an example of underfitting.
这是欠拟合的示例
Now, what if instead we try to fit a polynomial of large degree
那么 如果我们尝试拟合一个大角度的多项式呢
like this one?
就像这一个？
This polynomial does great in the training set, fits it perfectly, but
这个多项式在训练集上的表现很好 完美拟合了点
somehow it seems like it's not the best answer.
但它似乎并非最佳答案
It memorizes the training set and it fails to find good properties of
它记住了训练集 但未能找到训练集的
the training set that will generalize well to the testing set.
良好属性 以很好地泛化到测试集
So even though it performs well in the training set,
所以即使它在训练集上的表现很好
it will perform poorly on the testing set.
但在测试集上的效果会很差
This is an example of overfitting.
这是过拟合的例子
We can see underfitting in a classification model as well.
我们也会在分类模型中看到欠拟合
The red and
在这里 红色点
blue points seems to be nicely separated by a quadratic curve like this one.
和蓝色点似乎很好地被这条二次曲线分隔开了
When we try to use a line, the model doesn't fit the points properly, and
如果我们用直线的话 此模型不能正确地拟合点
it underfits.
会出现欠拟合
And when we try to fit in a curve that is very complicated,
如果我们尝试拟合到非常复杂的曲线
we end up with a model that is too complex.
最终会得到一个太过复杂的模型
And this may not do well in the testing set.
它在测试集上的效果会很差
Thus it overfits.
会出现过拟合
So here's a small summary.
那么我们简单总结一下
On one side, we get the errors due to high bias, or underfitting.
一方面 我们获得高偏差误差或欠拟合
This is where we oversimplify the problem and
这里我们过度简化了问题
our model is too simple to capture the complexity of our data.
我们的模型太简单 无法捕捉到数据的复杂性
On the other side, we get the errors due to high variance or overfitting.
另一方面 我们获得高方差误差或过拟合
This is when we overcomplicate the problem and our model is too complex and
我们在这里过度复杂化了问题 我们的模型太复杂
ends up memorizing our data instead of learning it.
以至于记住了数据 而非学习了它
Then in the middle, we've got the good model.
而中间的是最佳模型
When it comes to the training data,
在训练数据方面
the high bias model tends to not fit it well since it's just too simple a model.
高偏差模型因为太简单而欠拟合
The high variance model tends to fit the training data really well
高方差模型趋向于完美拟合训练数据
since it's designed for it.
因为它完全匹配了每个点
Finally, the good model tends to fit the training data well.
最终 最佳模型对训练数据的拟合刚刚好
Now, when it comes to the testing data,
然后 在测试数据方面
the high bias model tends to perform poorly.
高偏差模型的效果会很差
And so does the high variance model.
高方差模型也是
The good model is the one that performs well in the testing data.
而最佳模型在测试数据上的效果较好